Connor Lee

(425) 577-3605 | connorleee16@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/connorioshualee | github.com/connorleee | connorlee.me

Summary

Full Stack Software Engineer with 2+ years of experience developing complex applications with React, Node, SQL/NoSQL, REST, and team collaboration using Git version control. Driven to develop world changing software while working with passionate teams and cutting edge technologies.

Experience

Star Magnolia Apartments, LLC | Software Engineer

2020 - 2021

- Built internal tool with intuitive React front-end to manage property leases, finances, and maintenance requests
- Collaborated in application design/architecting and schema creation to meet client's needs and future plans
- Reduced repeat code by writing reusable custom React hook for form handling with validation
- Utilized bcrypt hashing to secure user data with password encryption on the backend
- Built front and back-end REST API to register users, handle user sessions, validate forms, and more
- Developed middleware to parse HTTP headers for JSON Web Tokens and handle authentication with private routes
- Hosted PostgreSQL database with AWS RDS to store user and lease data and allow simple future scaling
- Agile process with daily stand ups and weekly sprint meetings to communicate work scope and discuss blockers

ParkSmart Urban | Software Engineer

2019 - 2020

- Designed and implemented MySQL database and schema to support MVC architecture and relational data
- Researched and implemented Google Maps API with user geolocation as application's core UI
- Created CRUD routes from back-end to display database data on Google Maps on client side
- Built logic testing scripts using Mocha/Chai and Travis-CI to ensure application stability

Granite Construction Company | Project Engineer II

2016 - 2020

- Recognized regionally as leader in technology after developing drone solutions to enhance documentation, project planning, and quantity tracking which saved a project over \$250,000 in claims
- Managed teams of 10+ people to successfully build \$35,000,000 jobs and scopes of work over \$6,000,000

Personal Projects

Bug Tracker | bugtracker-cl.com | Readme

Project management tool to organize and organization's projects while featuring teams, issue tickets, comments, and more

- React front-end with re-usable custom hooks/components and dynamic content per user authorization level
- NodeJS backend with Express.js server to serve data from PostgreSQL relational database
- Persistent log-in sessions with authenticated API calls using JSON web tokens and local storage
- Responsive and intuitive user interface using Bootstrap framework to support desktop and mobile experiences

React Form Handler NPM Package | npmjs.com/package/useformcl | Readme

Custom React Hook to simplify React forms, handle developer defined validation, and reduce repeat code

- Locally handles state of form and returns standard React on Change and on Submit handlers
- Compatible with standard HTML form types and abstracts this repetitive logic from the developer
- Returns an object of error messages if form submission fails developer defined validation

Education and Public Talks

University of Washington | Full Stack Web Development - Immersive University of Washington | B.S. Civil and Environmental Engineering Technology in Construction | Northwest Construction Consumer Council

Technical Skills

Languages: Javascript, Java, SQL, NoSQL, HTML, CSS

Technologies: React, Node, Express, Git, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Oauth/JWT, Mocha/Chai, Jest, Bootstrap